# **Ari Abramowitz**, Full Stack Web Developer

(201) 994-6484 | ari.abramowitz1@gmail.com | ariabr.netlify.app | linkedin.com/in/ariabr | github.com/aribr

# **Summary**

Full stack web developer with experience in both startup and agile environments and Summa Cum Laude graduate of Rutgers University. I am a creative, organized and methodical problem solver with strong writing skills and a background in philosophy. I have a drive to learn new technologies and I am always ready for a new challenge.

## Skills

Frontend: JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Material-UI

Backend / Databases: Node, Python, Django, Java, Spring, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Express, Firebase

Other Tools: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Jasmine, Pytest, Jira, Trello

# **Experience**

Fullstack Software Engineer | Dynamic Healthcare Solutions 2020 - Present Python, Django, Postgres, JS

- · Developed software to enable efficient AR management for 75,000+ residents in 80 facilities across the US
- · Worked on a team of 6 developers in an Agile framework
- · Improved code quality by performing peer code reviews and incorporating other developers' suggestions
- · Wrote clear and detailed documentation to ease future development

#### **Software Developer | Taryag Analytics** React, Java, Spring, MySQL

2019 - 2020

- · Primary developer for a text mining and analytics startup
- Enabled 2020 Q1 beta launch by developing the frontend and backend for 6 new analysis features, including a sentence structure analyzer, a word cloud generator, and multiple text comparison tools
- · Improved comparative analysis capabilities by building a web-scraping ETL process to load new source data
- Quickly gained familiarity with Java and completed first major task within 3 weeks
- · Built effective solutions from rough requirements by researching options and finding optimal implementations

#### **Powered by Sefaria Contest** React, Java, Spring

2020

- · Frontend developer for team building a 3D family tree visualizer for the Powered by Sefaria contest
- · Awarded Honorable Mention and featured as a showcase project on the company's website

#### **Projects** React, Node, Express, Postgres, Firebase

2018 - 2020

- · Ezrat Nashim DB: Crowdsourced database designed to help users assess local synagogue options
- · Spotifake: Frontend-only music player application
- · Slaq: Chat app where users can sign in, create rooms and read, send, edit and delete messages
- · Tirred: Discussion board where users sign up, add posts and vote and comment on posts

### 2020

· Mindful Internet Use: Coded bug fix for Chrome productivity extension with 300+ users

# **Education**

## **Continuing Education**

Bloc | Web Developer Track

•	Test-Driven Development with Python (Harry Percival)	2021
	The Complete Junior to Senior Web Developer Roadmap (Udemy)	2020
	The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)	2020

## · The Ultimate Java Mastery Series (Code with Mosh)

2019

- · Built 5 cloud-hosted web-apps as part of an 8-month apprentice-style coding bootcamp
- · Mastered fundamental principles of software engineering and web development through project-based learning

## Rutgers University | BA | Summa Cum Laude | GPA: 3.94

2018

- · Majors: Philosophy, Jewish Studies; Minor: Religion
- · Semester Abroad: Honors Program, The Hebrew University of Jerusalem
- · Honor societies: Phi Beta Kappa; Natl. Society of Collegiate Scholars; Natl. Society of Leadership and Success